

PROFESSIONAL SYNOPSIS

15+ years of rich IT experience in collaborative development teams practicing automated testing and deployment utilizing **DevOps** tools.

Experience in Agile Scrum development methodologies & Exposure in Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe)

Experience in "Cloud Computing"

Experience in Robotic Process Automation (RPA).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

TOOLS & CLOUD COMPUTING:

ClearCase, Subversion, Git/GitHub, Gitlab, Jenkins, Maven, Nexus, SonarQube, AWS, Azure DevOps (VSTS), Jira, Confluence, Stride, HP Project Portfolio Management (aka Kintana), AutoRABIT, Ansible, Docker, OpenShift, Helm, Gremlin, GoCD, Sauce Labs, New Relic, Nagios, Sensu, Slack, ChatOps (Hu.bot), RocketChat, Workato, Remedy, ServiceNow, Opsgenie, PagerDuty.

RPA:

BluePrism, Automation Anywhere & UiPath

SENTHIL KUMAR CHANDRAN

DEVOPS ARCHITECT, AGILE DEVELOPMENT, CLOUD COMPUTING & RPA



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DEVOPS ARCHITECT • HCL TECHNOLOGIES LTD • MAR 2018 - TILL DATE

- DevOps & Automation SPOC for all Commercial Industries (CI) accounts.
- Worked on DevOps lab setup for HiTech accounts for showcasing the capability of process & tools to customers.
- Implemented ChatOps solutions with various DevOps tools.
- Worked on Application Migration project to OpenShift
- Defining DevOps roadmap and Conduct Assessments across all Commercial Industries (CI) accounts.
- Participate in RFP discussions, prepare solution documents for responses.

CROSS FUNCTIONAL LEAD • HCL TECHNOLOGIES LTD • JUL 2016 - FEB 2018

- DevOps & Automation Lead, Value Champion & People Champion.
- Managed a cross functional team of 16 Members to provide 24x7 support globally.
- Involved in Automating the Informatica ETL jobs monitoring by creating a separate monitoring console. (EOMC)
- SPOC for BCP Prepared Business Continuity Plan and executed test report simulation exercise.

CLOUD SUPPORT LEAD • HCL TECHNOLOGIES LTD • FEB 2016 - JUN 2016

- Managed a team of 12 Members of Cloud Support engineers to provide 24x7 support globally.
- Coordinate efforts in troubleshooting, deployments, upgrades and Sev1/Sev2 issues to ensure timely resolution of issues and provide status updates to the customer.

TECHNICAL LEAD • HCL TECHNOLOGIES LTD • JAN 2012 - JAN 2016

- Responsible for version control, build and deploy processes for Oracle EBS, Oracle ASCP, Oracle ADF, Oracle SOA (Middleware), Oracle BI, DWH & Java Projects.
- Design, develop, implement and support configuration plan, branching, build equations suitable for the Agile/scrum methodologies followed in programs/implementation.





TECHNICAL CERTIFICATION

Successfully completed "AWS Solutions Architect – Associate" certification

"Scrum Master Accredited Certification" from International Scrum Institute

IBM Certified Administrator - Rational ClearCase UNIX

Successfully completed RPA
Advanced Diploma certification from
UiPath

Certified Advanced RPA
Professional from "Automation
Anywhere"

Successful course completion certificate on "Red Hat OpenShift 3 Foundations"

Successfully completed "**IBM Blockchain** Foundation Developer" course from IBM developerWorks

Successful course completion certificate on "IBM Cloud Application Developer Certification Preparation"

Successful course completion certificate on "Oracle Cloud DevOps Tools and Solutions" (MOOC)

TRAININGS ATTENDED

Basis Tools & Technology Training, Bangalore – Automating **DevOps in SAP** (Transport Expresso, Shift Left, DevMax & Testimony)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED...

SR CONFIGURATION ANALYST • SCOPE INTERNATIONAL • SEP 2008 – JAN 2012

- Ensure ABG / AIG and SCM Plan reviewed and approved by application Team and SCM
- Administering SCM Tools like ClearCase, Subversion, & Jenkins etc.,

SOFTWARE ENGINEER • MELSTAR INFORMATION TECH LTD • SEP 2006 – AUG 2008

 Responsible for Build and Release Management for all Standard Chartered Bank applications.

TECHNICAL SUPPORT • AVANTAGE SOLUTIONS LTD • JUL 2004 - AUG 2006

 Supported Distributors and retailers in Tamil Nadu, also involved in training the channel partner's sales.
 Products: Bank Account Management System, ChequeMate

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of Business Administration • 2005 • UNIVERSITY OF MADRAS

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Business Champ Award by "Scope International" for 1st Quarter 2008
- Business Champ Award by "Scope International" for 4th Quarter 2009
- Technology Governance Award by "Scope International" for 1st Quarter 2010
- Values Champ Award by "Scope International" for 2nd Quarter 2010
- Sustainability Champ Team Award by "Scope International" for 2nd Quarter 2010
- Subversion Button Awards by "Brocade Comm. Systems, Inc" for 4th Ouarter 2012
- Value Creation Award by HCL Achieved more than a target (\$ Value) -
- Spot Award by HCL Achieved more than a target (\$ Value) 2013
- HCL Badminton Tournament 2016 (Runners) & 2017 (Winners)
- Have found few Bugs/Issues in Version control tools CollabNet Subversion, CollabNet Subversion Edge & GitHub. Vendor have accepted my cases and implemented in production.



